Contact

6823139204 (Mobile) dave.shubham@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/daveshubham (LinkedIn) dave-shubham.github.io/ (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Business Intelligence Extract, Transform, Load (ETL) Data Analysis

Languages

English

Hindi

Gujarati

Certifications

Exam 762: Developing SQL Databases

MCSA: SQL 2016 Database Development - Certified 2017

MCSE: Data Management and Analytics — Certified 2017

PH525.1x: Statistics and R

The Python Bible™ | Everything You Need to Program in Python

Honors-Awards

New Dean's Excellence Scholarship Hasnain and Rashida Saboowala International Merit Scholarship

Shubham Dave

Enterprising Software Engineer | Keen Learner Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Summary

As a firm believer in "Learning is forever", I continuously pursue learning, both formally and informally. Due to strong predilection for computers since childhood, I graduated in Information Technology from Nirma University. Apart from that, I am active participant in coding sites like HackerRank, Project Euler & HackerEarth and I completed CS50 course and "Statistics and R" course by Harvard University.

After graduating, I wanted to learn about the practical application of everything I learnt and so, I joined MAQ Software Pvt. Ltd., a 9-time honoree of Inc. 5000 companies. I worked on a diverse set of projects for handling ETLs, DB management & administration, generating user analytics, UI development, automated testing and other such areas for both frontend and backend solutions. Besides working for projects, I also managed my time and successfully completed 3 Microsoft certifications. Also, I worked in support request team, which helped in improving my customer service skills and aided in understanding the perspective of clients and customers better.

This experience made me understand my affinity to work with a company that creates creative solutions and has great impact in their customers' lives. However, I wanted to further improve upon my techno-management skills and subsequently, I joined IT and Management course at UT Dallas in Fall of 2017. I am planning to complete my graduation and pursue a career in a tech based customer centric company that creates innovative solutions.

Besides my work-life, I am an avid reader and love cycling & rock climbing.

Experience

The University of Texas at Dallas 6 months

Lead Parking Enforcement Officer August 2018 - Present

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

- Supervise and support all the Parking Enforcement Officers (PEO)
- Perform weekly scheduling of PEOs
- Training new members of PEOs and Lead PEOs
- Act as a University Ambassador by providing information and assistance to all customers
- Issue event permits for all events happening around the campus including special events such as Graduation Ceremony or VIP parking reservations
- Responsible for providing accurate information to PEOs to issue parking warning and citations in accordance with UTD Parking Rules and Regulations
- Manage departmental inventory for PEOs
- Provide verbal and/or written testimonies in court on criminal and civil matters related to UTD Parking

Parking Enforcement Officer

June 2018 - August 2018 (3 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

- Responsible for field patrol of UTD parking locations and zones
- Issue parking warning and citations in accordance with UTD parking rules and regulations
- Inform management about levels of utilization and any issues that need to be addressed
- Monitor parking meters and parking regulation signage, reporting any inoperative meters or sign damage observed
- Act as a university ambassador, providing information and assistance
- · Guide or assist with training beginner staff
- Provide verbal and/or written testimonies in court on criminal and civil matters related to UTD parking
- Assist with special event parking such as graduation or VIP parking reservations

MAQ Software
Software Engineer
August 2016 - August 2017 (1 year 1 month)
Mumbai Area, India

- Owned complete backend development and deployment for multiple Business Intelligence (BI) websites
- Created cross-browser compatible UI using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery/Angular JS/JavaScript to filter and display multi-dimensional Business Intelligence data
- Developed the service layer API for receiving the user inputs and fetching data from backend using C#
- Designed and enhanced queries, views, stored procedures and functions to display multi-dimensional BI data based on user parameters using T-SQL and SSMS
- Automated processes for fetching and manipulating data using ETL packages reducing efforts of the team by a factor of 10 using SSIS
- Built dashboards to display user analytics data with different visualizations in Power BI online using Azure Application Insights and Stream Analytics
- Innovated an automated testing solution to compare values from backend and Power BI reports for verification and provide mail alerts using C# and Selenium, reducing 80% efforts for finding discrepancies
- Administered roles and data access for different roles to restrict access as per multiple parameters including user location and employee role using SSMS
- Deployed frontend and service solutions on Azure Portal
- Provided round-the-clock support for deployed solutions to worldwide users

Education

Naveen Jindal School of Management, UT Dallas Master of Science - MS, Information Technology and Management · (2017 - 2019)

Institute of Technology, Nirma University
Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Information Technology · (2012 - 2016)

C. C. Shah Sarvajanik High School 12th, Mathematics and Computer Science · (2010 - 2012)

H.M.B. Sardar High School

8th-10th, High School/Secondary Diplomas and Certificates · (2008 - 2010)